Man of God, help me.
I’m afflicted by a stiff neck due to cervical spondylosis
and a knee problem due to osteoarthritis with torn cartilages.
My name is Professor Ddembe Williams.
I’m a professor of complex systems and mathematics.
I cannot teach anymore because I cannot stand.
I can’t do research because I cannot sit for long.
Please, help me.
I have been everywhere, in every hospital; I had the best physicians and consultants but to no avail.
I knew that my last bus stop would be this place.
After your healing and deliverance, you should be ready to render your services
for some months, in Africa here.
Yes.
Thank you, sir.
Your wife...
because you have challenges.
Yes.
It's God that saved you.
So, after the healing, we’ll talk about that.
Thank you, Man of God.
There's a boy.
Yes.
Where’s this boy?
Back in United Kingdom.
But he’s not with you.
No, he’s not with me.
That is why I’m asking you.
Because these are the issues we are going to work on.
Amen.
But this is not the time to talk about that now.
Healing In Jesus’ Name
Thank You, Jesus.
OK, can you remove all this?
Healing In Jesus’ Name
Stand up.
Turn your neck.
Thank You, Jesus, I'm healed!
I can run!
Prof Ddembe Williams
Healed In Jesus’ Name
Thank You, Jesus.
Prof Ddembe Williams
Healed In Jesus’ Name
I feel free. I feel light, very light!
TESTIMONY TIME
He is a picture of good health, to the glory of God.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
Good morning, Church.
My name is Professor Ddembe Williams.
I am a professor of complex systems & data analytics.
I'm from the United Kingdom.
What brought me to The SCOAN is affliction in my neck.
I had stiff neck and that caused severe pain; I could not turn or bend.
It also caused paralysis in my heart.
I also had osteoarthritis in my knees; later it emerged that I had torn cartilages in my knees.
Basically, walking, standing and sitting was difficult; I lived in pain.
It was some time back when my maid and my driver said,
"You know, we've seen people being healed at Emmanuel TV".
I said, "Which one is that?"
That was 6 months ago.
I started watching, got inspiration, built up my faith and kept on praying.
Even if I slept in the lounge, I would switch on my Emmanuel TV,
to have it on in the background while I was sleeping.
I could not sit for long to write my papers.
By the time I finished my PhD I had already about 20 papers, but I could not write this time,
I could not go to class to teach my PhD or Masters class, because I couldn't stand for long.
An hour was utmost and I would still be in severe pain.
That affected me, my career because I wasn't contributing to my job,
and my institution started getting worried, looking for an alternative to replace me,
put me on leave and so forth.
That affected certainly my performance, but also my family.
My wife had all the time to miss her daily routine, her job to take me to the hospital.
For example: Every winter I had to go to the hospital and she had to push me in a wheelchair.
When I was travelling, I was seated in the wheelchair.
It became very cumbersome for me to do any job, or any useful contribution to society and my own family.
You said you went to various hospitals.
Medically, what did the doctors try to do to help you with this condition?
Medically, I went to many hospitals as you said, so many consultants...
As you know in the UK to get a consultant takes quite a long time,
but when I saw them, they could not really specify medications for me to be healed.
They gave me painkillers.
In a day I would take about 8 different tablets.
I was a kind of a walking pharmacy and it became really problematic,
because my local GP (general practitioner) said, "It might be that you will never get a cure for that,
you will live with these medications all your life".
So, it became very difficult.
It is the Holy Spirit who led me to The SCOAN.
I could not directly get my visa in the UK,
so I had to go to Nairobi where I managed to get a visa and then I came here.
When I came here, I was welcomed and put in the prayer line.
When the man of God came near me, while he was preaching,
it seemed as if he was preaching to me all the time.
I kind of kept on getting uplifting...
By the time he reached me, I was already done, because I could only hear his voice,
the congregation kind of disappeared.
I could only hear his voice and I was responding to his voice all the time.
When the man of God approached me and touched my left arm to the shoulder,
there was a hammer all the time.
I really felt a big punch of a hammer hitting me wherever he touched me.
It wasn't easy.
I could see his hand moving lightly like this, but it was translated to the body as a big hammer.
That kept on building up, until he said, "Stand up", and I just found myself standing up.
Wow, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
And since that day, sir, what are the changes in your life, health, everything about you?
Phenomenal - that's what.
Right from that day, I started walking and I haven't stopped.
I think people whom I've been with; going to the prayer mountain -
they have seen - I've been all the time trying, and now I can use my legs properly,
I can twist my neck - no problem at all; the arm is doing very well.
For the first time in 5 years, I went to the prayer mountain, knelt and prayed to my God.
So, I would like to really recommend to the viewers all over the world and in the congregation
that it is only Jesus and faith that can work.
Also to my academics: I know there are diverging views between scientific endeavour and the biblical Word.
I think those views are converging now.
I'm an example where convergence of scientific and God's views are coming together.
When you have a miracle like this, we scientists say, "This is unexplained",
but I want to tell the whole world that that unexplained is Jesus plus faith.
And that's what really healed me.
The Holy Spirit helped me to build my faith and with the prayers Jesus really located me,
and gave me this healing through the grace of the man of God
whom Jesus used as His channel to heal people like myself.
Amen, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
Sir, can you just now demonstrate what you can now do that you couldn't do before, to the glory of God.
Well, I can walk smartly in front of my students and give a lecture.
I can do many things; maybe I'm going to start playing football.
And of course, I can shake my neck and twist my hands, which I was not able to do earlier.
It is amazing.
I can testify that since last week Saturday, I have not taken a single tablet;
whethers painkiller, whether vitamins - nothing at all.
Jesus is my medication.
Amen, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
Just a final question, sir:
During your encounter with the man of God, he actually gave you a Word of prophecy concerning your son.
Can you just confirm how that Word of prophecy is also true for your life?
Actually, the man of God gave me two prophecies; one was about my son.
Yes, we have a child...
All my kids, I would say are brilliant as academics, they pursue their academic endeavours excellently,
but we have one who really can't progress.
We have tried to support him, taking him to psychologists, sociologists, psychiatrists,
but of no avail.
With the prophecy, I'm sure that has now come to an end;
he will be able to progress forward like any other child.
Amen, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
And he also prophesied about my wife.
We had challenges and I'm glad that...
Today, when I woke up in the morning, my wife was the first one to wish me the best for today -
so, that's already a breakthrough.
TT ROBERT BEGIER 14/12/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 17/12/2018